MARK SCHWARTZ

Oakhurst, NJ 07755 / (732) 614-0224 / mschwartz402@gmail.com

Trusted and respected leader with hands-on expertise for leading technology, strategy and operations to drive notable business growth. Skilled building enterprise infrastructure and driving technology innovation to support business transformation and expansion. Strong business strategy, risk management, compliance, cybersecurity and M&A experience. Cultivated long lasting, trusted relationships with vendors, customers and internal teams.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Strong knowledge of state and federal regulation compliance.

Ability to weigh business risk and enforce appropriate information security measures.

Strong negotiation skills. (employees, unions and vendors)

Plan the implementation of new systems and provide guidance to professionals and other staff within the organization.

Design and customize technological systems and platforms to improve the customer/user experience.

Monitor changes or advancements in technology to discover ways the company can gain a competitive advantage.

Analyze the costs, value, and risks of current business processes and procedures to advise management and suggest strategic directions.

EXPERIENCE

Kiely Business Services, Tinton Falls, NJ

Chief Compliance Officer (March 2018 to December 2018)

- Worked with EMT and created an effective growth strategy to propel the business from a standalone construction company to a multi-faceted business conglomerate of multiple business units both organically and through acquisition.
- Successfully oversaw all union contract negotiations, contract changes and amendments.
- Directed and oversaw all facilities management and security. Oversaw the build out of all new facilities.
- Oversaw fleet management and purchasing. Reviewed specifications and purchasing agreements.
- Worked with vendor for complete DOT compliance audit. Reviewed recommendations and facilitated changes as necessary.
- Worked with EMT to create an expanded Safety and Training team and programs to help reduce the EMR to a historic low of .358.
- Worked with EMT team to create a Union Apprentice program registered with the US Department of Labor. Directed and provided audit and compliance recommendations for the program and made sure the program met regulatory compliance.
- Established compliance program for a \$350 million construction, engineering, project management, consulting, job site traffic safety, real estate, equipment rentals, and fleet man-

- agement; designed strategy, policies/procedures and management system to ensure federal, state and local regulatory requirements and governance were met.
- Led comprehensive review of all business units, companies, departments, programs, policies and vendors for regulatory, environmental, audit and for Sarbanes-Oxley compliance issues.
- Oversaw risk management, managing claims/lawsuits across all business units, working closely with insurance companies and attorneys in reducing and limiting exposure.
- Developed plan and training to combat phishing and social engineering scams across all business units.
- Created internal compliance monitoring system for all areas of the business units.

J. F. Kiely Group, Long Branch, NJ

Chief Information/Technology Officer (January 2007 to March 2018)

- Led information technology vision, strategy and operations; built infrastructure and oversaw cybersecurity and risk management as member of executive team that drove business growth as revenue increased to over \$350 million.
- Developed, managed, coached and mentored a dedicated Internal IT staff and contracted with external consulting staff for optimization of growth and workload.
- Spearheaded and led all of the technology upgrades and initiatives throughout all of the business units.
- Oversaw risk management, managing data privacy and claims/lawsuits across all business areas, working closely with insurance companies and attorneys.
- Played critical role in business transformation, change and lifecycle management, brand development and financial/operational decisions during period of significant expansion.
- Developed innovative enterprise systems that leveraged data analytics and business intelligence to drive efficiency and growth; designed applications for risk management, fleet management, inventory, equipment, vehicle/crew tracking and time sheets/billing.
- Managed multimillion dollar IT budget, negotiated vendor contracts for equipment and consulting services and various service and maintenance contracts.
- Key member of M&A team; evaluated technology and led integration, systems migration and infrastructure optimization for 5 acquisitions.
- Designed and optimized networks/systems, cloud storage, disaster recovery plans and digital building security across all offices and sites (18 locations).
- Developed and provided all of the IT functions for the 7 business units. This included construction, engineering, project management, consulting, job site traffic safety, real estate, equipment rentals, and fleet management.
- Developed and provided help desk system across all business units and provide controls for change management, incident reporting, problem management, audit, internal controls and security. Provided all technical support to all business units.

J. F. Kiely Construction Co., Long Branch, NJ

Director of IT Operations (1993 to 2007)

- Developed technology solutions and infrastructure to support company diversification and expansion; built data centers, storage facilities, security systems and redundancies and managed telecommunications.
- Designed IT processes, procedures and policies to optimize efficiency and effectiveness and deliver agile solutions.

- Built a robust construction workflow and management system that improved project tracking/ billing and customer communications.
- Implemented Sage accounting system to accommodate increased volume and complex transactions.
- Developed a mobile application for traffic control management and launched company's first website.
- Managed highly successful union contract negotiations, collaborating with outside counsel.

•

J. F. Kiely Construction Co., Long Branch, NJ

Data & Systems Analyst

- Designed and implemented company's first computerized accounting systems and built programs to manage fleet, bidding, job costing and customer management.
- Developed networks, built servers and oversaw hardware, software and telecommunications; managed enterprise and staff IT support.

SKILLS

Cloud Applications (AWS/Azure/Google)

Windows Server Administration SQL Server Administration

Terminal Services Administration Citrix Virtual Apps and Desktop

VMWare Administration

Ubuntu Server Administration
Data Backup and Recovery

Business Continuity Management Facility Security Access Administration

Network Access Security

Network Design Communication Decision Making

Self-motivation Leadership Teamwork Integrity Office 365/ MS Licensing

Cisco LAN and Core Switch Administration

Cisco Wireless Administration Cisco Router Administration Cisco Unified Communications

Server Virtualization Firewall Administration Disaster Recovery Solutions

Security Controls Risk Assessment Cyber Security

Communication Skills

Organized

Task Management Conflict Resolution

Adaptability Creativity Vision

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Former Volunteer Firefighter, Borough of Farmingdale, NJ
- Volunteer, St. Bernard Project, Sea Bright, NJ
- Class A CDL, Hazmat/Tanker/Air Brake endorsements
- Early career at the **New Jersey Board of Public Utilities**, holding progressive responsibility automating systems, building networks and developing/leading staff training programs.

EDUCATION

Montclair State University, Upper Montclair, NJ *Bachelor of Science*, Business Administration